Hi this is Nigel Gregory with Blue Griffin Handyman.
Today we're going to show you how to use a hammer safely.
Now for most projects you probably don't want to use a hammer this big.
But today we're just going to use this framing hammer.
Now when you use a hammer it's always important to wear your safety gear.
Good eye-protection and sometimes even ear-protection always help in a job.
Now to start you take your nail, you take your hammer, and to fasten two pieces of wood together you put your nail down and you hit the head of the nail just to secure it into the piece of wood.
Just lightly like that.
Once you have it standing by itself, hold the two pieces of wood down and really let it go.
Don't grip the hammer too hard, kind of loosely and use a good deal of momentum.
Watch your face when you come up.
Don't bring it up too high.
But just lightly let the hammer fall.
And that was how to use a hammer safely.